<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE refentry PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN" "http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd">
<refentry lang="en">
<refmeta>
<refentrytitle>smdba-netswitch</refentrytitle>
<manvolnum>1</manvolnum>
</refmeta>
<refnamediv>
    <refname>smdba-netswitch</refname>
    <refpurpose>Orace database server network listening mode switcher.</refpurpose>
</refnamediv>
<refsynopsisdiv id="_synopsis">
<simpara><emphasis role="strong">smdba-netswitch</emphasis> <emphasis>COMMAND</emphasis></simpara>
</refsynopsisdiv>
<refsect1 id="_description">
<title>DESCRIPTION</title>
<simpara>The smdba-netswitch(1) command changes Oracle database listening from
"world-wide" to "localhost-only" and vice versa. It is highly recommended to
use "localhost-only" mode in order to address possible remote attacks,
exploiting security holes in Oracle database.</simpara>
</refsect1>
<refsect1 id="_important">
<title>IMPORTANT</title>
<simpara>This tool is not working with any other database vendor.</simpara>
</refsect1>
<refsect1 id="_commands">
<title>COMMANDS</title>
<variablelist>
<varlistentry>
<term>
<emphasis role="strong">localhost</emphasis>
</term>
<listitem>
<simpara>
    Set Oracle database and its listeners listening only to the <emphasis>localhost</emphasis> or
    "<emphasis>127.0.0.1</emphasis>" loopback. This will make impossible to access the database
    remotely in any way.
</simpara>
</listitem>
</varlistentry>
<varlistentry>
<term>
<emphasis role="strong">worldwide</emphasis>
</term>
<listitem>
<simpara>
    Set Oracle database and its listeners listening incoming connections
    world-wide, or to "<emphasis>0.0.0.0</emphasis>". This will make possible to access the
    database remotely with any tools.
</simpara>
</listitem>
</varlistentry>
</variablelist>
</refsect1>
<refsect1 id="_warning">
<title>WARNING!</title>
<simpara>If your Oracle database is listening world-wide, you directly exposing
potential security holes in the Oracle ecosystem. It is <emphasis>highly recommended</emphasis> to
turn world-wide listeners <emphasis role="strong">OFF</emphasis>, by switching listeners to <emphasis role="strong">localhost only</emphasis>.</simpara>
</refsect1>
<refsect1 id="_author">
<title>AUTHOR</title>
<simpara>SMDBA-NETSWITCH was originally written by Bo Maryniuk &lt;<ulink url="mailto:bo@suse.de">bo@suse.de</ulink>&gt;</simpara>
</refsect1>
<refsect1 id="_resources">
<title>RESOURCES</title>
<simpara>Source code at GitHub: <ulink url="http://github.com/suse/smdba">http://github.com/suse/smdba</ulink></simpara>
<simpara>SUSE Manager web site: <ulink url="http://www.suse.com/products/suse-manager/">http://www.suse.com/products/suse-manager/</ulink></simpara>
</refsect1>
<refsect1 id="_copying">
<title>COPYING</title>
<simpara>The MIT License (MIT)</simpara>
<simpara>Copyright (c) 2012 SUSE Linux Products GmbH</simpara>
<simpara>Permission is hereby granted, free of charge, to any person obtaining
a copy of this software and associated documentation files (the "Software"),
to deal in the Software without restriction, including without limitation the
rights to use, copy, modify, merge, publish, distribute, sublicense, and/or
sell copies of the Software, and to permit persons to whom the Software is
furnished to do so, subject to the following conditions:</simpara>
<simpara>The above copyright notice and this permission notice shall be included in all
copies or substantial portions of the Software.</simpara>
<simpara>THE SOFTWARE IS PROVIDED "AS IS", WITHOUT WARRANTY OF ANY KIND, EXPRESS OR
IMPLIED, INCLUDING BUT NOT LIMITED TO THE WARRANTIES OF MERCHANTABILITY,
FITNESS FOR A PARTICULAR PURPOSE AND NONINFRINGEMENT. IN NO EVENT SHALL THE
AUTHORS OR COPYRIGHT HOLDERS BE LIABLE FOR ANY CLAIM, DAMAGES OR OTHER
LIABILITY, WHETHER IN AN ACTION OF CONTRACT, TORT OR OTHERWISE, ARISING FROM,
OUT OF OR IN CONNECTION WITH THE SOFTWARE OR THE USE OR OTHER DEALINGS IN THE
SOFTWARE.</simpara>
</refsect1>
</refentry>
